Cammie Newmyer

Data Scientist, Machine Learning Specialist

613 4th St. Apt. B Alamosa, CO 81101 (719) 588-4570 newmyer.mtms@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Math That Makes Sense - Alamosa, CO Data Scientist

JAN 2013 - PRESENT

Responsible for the entire data science process, from identifying and collecting data, to cleaning and analyzing, to creating and implementing models, to presenting insights and recommendations to clients or stakeholders.

UCCS, CCCO, Pueblo CC - Colorado Springs, CO College Math Instructor

AUG 2016 - MONTH 2020

Contract-based instructor who provided teaching in statistics and mathematics at the college and university level.

National Science Foundation - Arlington, VA

Albert Einstein Distinguished Educator Fellow

AUG 2018 - AUG 2019

Conducting research and analysis on STEM education policies and programs, developing and implementing STEM education initiatives, advising federal agencies and policymakers on STEM education issues, collaborating with federal agencies and organizations to promote STEM education, participating in professional development opportunities and sharing their experiences with the larger STEM education community.

Secondary Public Education - San Luis Valley, CO *Mathematics, Computer Science and STEM Research Teacher*

20+ YEARS

Responsible for planning and delivering lessons that help students develop a deep understanding of mathematical concepts and skills, as well as building their problem-solving and critical thinking abilities.

EDUCATION

Regis University, Denver, CO — MS Data Science

MAR 2020 - PRESENT

Graduate-level program advancing the skills and knowledge needed to analyze and interpret large and complex data sets covering a wide range of topics in data science, including statistical analysis, machine learning, data visualization, and big data technologies.

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

5+ years of analytics / data science experience

Strong proficiency in programming and statistical analysis

Comfortable manipulating data with Python, R, SQL

Experience designing and analyzing experiments

MS in Data Science (expected 2023)

MA in Mathematics (2011)

Life-Long Learner

Statistics Instructor

Ability to translate non-technical business requirements into technical solutions, and translate technical solutions to business outcomes

Author and National Presenter

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- R
- SQL
- Pandas
- NumPy
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Reinforcement Learning
- Natural Language Processing
- Tableau
- Excel
- Matplotlib
- Anaconda
- Spyder
- Jupyter Notebook
- Google Colab
- GCP
- GitHub
- Mathematical Modeling
- Predictive Modeling

University of Houston, Houston, TX — MA Mathematics

IUN 2008 - AUG 2011

Graduate-level program advancing a deep understanding of mathematical concepts and theories, as well as the skills needed to apply these ideas to real-world problems in mathematics and statistics.

Adams State University, Alamosa, CO — BA Mathematics

JUN 1997 - MAY 2000

Undergraduate-level program advancing an understanding of mathematical concepts and secondary education theories, as well as the skills needed to manage projects and communicate effectively in order to instruct students in mathematics, computer science, and statistics.

HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

iVentureVMS - Data Scientist, Machine Learning Specialist

Digital Commodities and Currency Mining startup. As part of the Regis University Innovation Challenge, provide data analytics, statistical analysis, machine learning, modeling, visualization.

Human Time Perception - Data Scientist

Preliminary investigation of how humans perceive time and its impact on mental health. Meet with current International Space Station researcher Gilles Clement, PhD. Meet with human communication researcher, Arthur "Skip" Lupia, PhD regarding future research in quantifying human time perception. Presentation with John B. Charles, PhD, at Space Center Houston, Houston, TX.

SLV Water Project - Data Scientist

Saguache County, CO. Inform stakeholders of possible errors in the current State water engineering model for the underground aquifer. All stages of the data cycle from experimental design, data acquisition, data structure, data analysis, presentation of results.

Town of Moffat Excise Tax - Data Scientist

Inform stakeholders of irregularities with regard to Town excise tax calculation and collection. All stages of the data cycle from experimental design, data acquisition, data structure, data analysis, presentation of results.

Political Candidate Campaign Analysis - Data Scientist

Alamosa, CO. Inform successful political candidate of voter demographics with respect to votes for and against. All stages of the data cycle from experimental design, data acquisition, data structure, data analysis, presentation of results.

HIGHLIGHTED PRESENTATIONS

<u>Saguache County Water Well Data</u> <u>Analysis</u>, Saguache, CO

<u>Does Anybody Really Know What</u> <u>Time It Is?</u> Presentation at Space Center Houston with Dr. John Charles

NSF Grant Writing Workshop, Mayaguez, Puerto Rico

<u>Human Time Perception and Mental</u> <u>Health</u>, Arlington, VA

<u>Improving STEM Outcomes</u>, Adams State University, Alamosa, CO

National Noyce Summit, Washington DC

Mathematical Group Theory. Isomorphic to Z, Colorado State University

HIGHLIGHTED ASSOCIATIONS

Association for Women in Mathematics, Student Chapter President

Mathematical Association of America

American Statistical Society

AUTHOR BOOKS

Math That Makes Sense Vol. 1, 2015

Math That Makes Sense Vol. 2, 2016

Math That Makes Sense Vol. 3, 2017

Math That Makes Sense Vol. 4, 2018